think of magic from Cleveland without
the work and the Legacy and the impact
of the individuals that were here
honoring tonight so thank you for
everything that you've done and I also
want to add my thanks to Dan and Dad
Mason you wouldn't be gathered here but
for these two individuals recognizing
the value of celebrating immigrants the
immigrants contributions and Legacy that
they have left that's made Cleveland a
rich city in their history
it's my honor on behalf of the Union
American Community tonight to present to
Mr suda a production and conclusive
International Hall Club
Mr sat there arrived to Greater women
like many as a graduate student
it has since made it his help building a
successful business building in the
community
and doing both humility
the focus on service but through both
leaving and enduring impact behind
Google
I had a chance to collect some of the
impressions of the Union Community about
Mr Southaven is the Legacy in Europe I
want to start with whatever
it's fellow neck teasing Hall of Fame Mr
refugees Tony
who was his first boss
he left a very strong first impression
of Oxford
Express for those of you that know
citizens said
you can't judge a man by his clothes
but he has always been the most stylish
and most impeccably entirely
entrepreneur among all of us and for
those of you that see through the show
tonight I had the honor of seeing
through the on Saturday morning for
a rise against under event and is
dressed exactly because
hahaha
citizens started his career here at a
polygon somebody's company who would
rather Jim had to say was it was one of
the key team members who helped building
companies to reach a level of success
that can machine
one of his greatest qualities was his
ability to convey and convince even the
most challenging customers to trust
trust this point of view and Trust his
expertise trust the solutions
and through that
bring even the most difficult and
complex customers issues to resolution
so the shed would not be satisfied his
employee property he always knew that he
would probably one day start his own
business that was his testimony and
indeed in 1990 shortly after achieving
citizenship he launched a few Concepts
his own successful Enterprise
through which he's developed products
and processes and urban patents for
their use throughout the steel industry
today
new Concepts as a supplier of various
Metals raw materials across the industry
come in every nearly every steel mill in
North America is one of its customers
in addition to being devoted to building
his company
throughout this life he has been devoted
to building the Indian Community
and also the Indian communities impact
Theory Cleveland
through the Indian Community has been
involved with the Federation for the
Indian Community associations on and
Indian association help enhance and has
also been very active in building the
Indian cultural networks which we've
learned about in our first two arteries
and with the engineer ing Engineers
helped lead its impact on Cleveland and
broader sense whether it's through the
work serving Refugee populations
U.S committee for refugees and
immigrants
supporting the Breakthrough schools in
the Hampton Academy school as well as
Project Life values and action
of all of that he's rallied to help the
Union Community here support the Union
Community
through programs that help children find
food as well as children given education
is one of our Indie committee members
Ricky Mana said the current president
FICA on a personal level
he does not say no to anyone
who's one of the most generous and
genuine individuals that we've had in
the community one of our true gems
ladies and gentlemen it is my honor
tonight to present to you
[Applause]
good evening
[Music]
thank you baiju for that singulatingly
warm introduction
Cleveland International Hall of Fame
Dan and Debbie
my fellow inductees
ladies and gentlemen
namaste
I accept
this induction
with humility
and traffic
today you have felicited me
in two ways in two dimensions
first I get to share this recognition
with those communities tall words
whose life stories are as impressive
as are there contributions to Cleveland
ladies and gentlemen congratulations
thank you
and secondly I'm honored to be in the
long list of illustrious Indian
Americans who have received this honor
before me
some of whom are in attendance today
thank you
there are many organizations that
recognize individual achievement
but Cleveland International Hall of Fame
is the only organization that directly
and specifically honors the cultural
heritage of all achievements ethnic
communities let's give them a big hand
as an immigrant
I stand at an intersection
an intersection of American hospitality
American greatness
and the cultural heritage and education
that I carried with me
some 40 years ago
when I had the Good Fortune to arrive in
this country to study for masters in
chemical engineering at University of
Africa
I found a country that was born and
welcoming
even as the winters were unimaginably
free
I found in America that made your life
easy
from the great interstate system to
Planes Trains automobiles
Telecommunications
but more interestingly
the American society provides margins
for success by that I mean if you have a
good idea
the society is ready with all the
support for instance
in many countries if you were to come up
with a great
recipe for ketchup
you would also need to own the modeling
plant the labeling plan your own trucks
and your own shelf space
but here in the USA
all of that support the logistics module
the finance module the regulatory
modules
are ready and available
to anyone
that's the reason a business that starts
in a garage
can lead to a billion dollars in no time
as many Tech Industries have done
but you know what is even more important
it is the honesty and integrity of its
people
imagine how pleasantly surprised I was
the awkward
to see that you can drop a quarter
open a box of newspapers
and everyone
just takes one
this honesty and integrity permeates
other Realms of life as well
for those who doubt this
I say to them
travel the world
the second half of immigrant equation
is how by culture
the Indian culture
cohabits and enriches
and United States for World At Large
and I speak here
for all of the Indian American diaspora
Indian history and culture is arguably
the longest
continuously extended story
and language is the soul of culture the
Sanskrit language is arguably the oldest
written and spoken language in the world
and as such is an elder sister of many
languages in the world including English
it will probably surprise many
that release the Sanskrit that provides
the root
for words like mother father brother
sister can be navigation juggernaut
September October November and December
among others
another Legacy is mathematics
Indian Society produced numbers 29
and made them operational
with the Magnificent invention we call
zero
only then the numbers became the number
system
numbers from 1 to Infinity
and infinite numbers from one to zero
the so-called decimal numbers were made
possible because of zero
but the bigger contribution to the
world's well-being
came not from the numbers themselves
but from the rationale
the paradigm shift
that made the humanity realize they
needed the numbers
and that Paradigm Shift was in the age
of battles and Conquest you simply took
all of the conquered regions stuff there
was no need to come but somewhere in
India said this is not a good idea let's
see if we can trade and trade
equitatively and if you want to trade
equitably you have to now invent the
concept called Counting
and concept of counting
requires the invention of numbers hence
the numbers
but India's greatest contribution to the
world
is its delving into the Mysteries of the
month
as Western science has looked outward
to understand its workings
Indian yogis and Mystics turned their
days in Word
into the world of consciousness
and found it to be of matching
complexity and vastness
these ancient Mystics try to answer the
existential questions
of how is it that we are here in the
first place
and to what purpose
what is moral and why
they experienced Oneness
the interconnectedness of all that is
it gave rise to an Sanskrit phrasing
which means the world is one family
on this one Earth and has but one future
the enlightenment philosophers
and the boss of them all the great
Emmanuel Kant
were influenced by this philosophy
the claiming and comedy of the Mind
is indispensable
even in the Modern Age
because after all the battles and
conquests
all the gadgets and scientific
discoveries
one last struggle remains
and that is for the moment of pure inner
peace and contentment
[Applause]
in my personal Journey
I was fortunate to have the steadfast
support of my family
my beautiful caring and resourceful wife
who makes my best better
and two gorgeous kids that are our pride
and joy
but also our large circle of friends
that are our family
our oxygen
and we surely survived kovid because of
you thank you
[Applause]
again
Cleveland International Hall of Fame
thank you for this honor namaste
all right